Guide to the D. Michael Fisher Papers, 1969-2004 AIS.2007.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- 2002 Gubernatorial Campaign, 1975-2002; V.
  - Finances, 1999-2002; 5.
    - Fundraising Events, January 12-May 30, 2002
      - Republican Governors Association 8th Annual Reception, February 25, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Jeb Bush, Florida, February 28, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Dinner with Chester County friends, March 7-8, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Sourbeer dinner thank you notes, March 12, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Somerset County reception/ PAUCA dinner, March 13, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Mike Fisher dinner in Washington, DC, March 20, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Harrisburg fundraiser, March 26, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Northumberland County evening reception, March 27, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - President Bush private reception thank you notes, April 2, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - W.A. Hawkins Associates fundraiser, April 3, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Southeast Young Republican for Fisher luncheon - Reed Smith, April 4, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - Dinner with Roy Zimmerman, April 9, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Fred DiBora home event, April 10, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Berks County reception, April 16, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Franklin Shoeneman home event, Schuykill County, April 16, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Towanda fundraiser at Bradford County museum, April 23, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Columbia County breakfast, April 23, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Pike County luncheon fundraiser, April 24, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Susquehanna County breakfast, April 24, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - The Honorable Lita and Stanley Cohen and Councilman Brian O'Neill fundraiser, April 26, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - Dale High fundraiser, April 26, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - Mario Mele event, April 28, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Lancaster breakfast, May 11, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Chester County fundraising dinner, May 14, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - Lewisburg luncheon, May 28, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - Triad Strategies/PA Orthopedics Association, May 30, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 64)
      - Philadelphia roundtable with Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, May 30, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - Pittsburgh Westin Convention Center for November 5, 2002 election night, July 14, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Major Donor Files, 2002
      - Major Donor Files (Box 7, Folder 1-6, Box 6)
    - Subject Files, 1999-2002
      - Fisher for Governor electronic files -- budget, briefings, donations, and event information (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Campaign finance reports, January 24, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Mail-in contributions (sampled) (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Fisher for Governor and Friends of Michael Fisher certified public accountant reports, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Leadership Finance Committee (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Pro-life donations, November 6, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Staff salary report, February 2002 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Mike Fisher's Political Career Files, 1975-1999; 6.
    The DMF Political Career sub-series contains samples of Fisher's work throughout his political career. It includes a profile of his legislative record in the House and Senate; platform and opposition information from his initial gubernatorial campaign in 1994; and overview information and press releases from his time as Attorney General.
    - House of Representatives and Senate, 1975-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial candidate, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial candidate -- Ridge/Schweiker campaign information, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Attorney General, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Issue Files, 1978-2002; 7.
    The Issue Files sub-series is comprised of issues important to Fisher's campaign. They contain correspondence, news clips, press releases, reports, and other materials documenting his commitment to various campaign topics.
    - Fisher and Earll biographies, profiles, and important campaign issues overview, May 3, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Agriculture (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Anti-trust law, 1986-2000 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Brag file, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Campaign issues briefing notebook (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Includes briefings on: economy, education, property taxes, agriculture, environment, state liquor stores, water, prescription drugs, transportation, redevelopment, Ed Rendell, and Bob Casey.
    - Death penalty, 1978-2002 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Employment, economy, jobs files (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Firemen (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Net operating loss (NOL), 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Pro-life (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Right-to-know law/open records law, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Sportsmen (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Fisher's positions, 1996-2002 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      Includes Fisher's positions on: economy/jobs in Pennsylvania, healthcare, and the environment.
    - Veterans (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Liquor Control Board, 1981-2002; 8.
    The Liquor Control Board (LCB) sub-series contains information related to Pennsylvania's Liquor Control Board and the state stores for alcohol contribution. It primarily contains Gov. Tom Ridge's materials and research on the privatization of the LCB and a small amount of information from Gov. Dick Thornburgh. These were likely research materials for Mike Fisher and his promise to privatize the LCB should he be elected governor (see, AIS.2007.07: Mike Fisher Papers, box 8, ff 1, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh).
    - Clippings, August 19, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Governor Ridge -- LCB Agendas, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Governor Ridge -- LCB memorandum and correspondence, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Governor Ridge -- LCB reports and presentations, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Governor Ridge -- LCB statements, news releases, and liquor control information, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Reports -- Privatization analysis, January 6, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Governor Thornburgh materials, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - News Clipping Packets, 1988-2002; 9.
    The News Clip Packets sub-series is almost comprised entirely of photocopied newspaper articles. Each folder contains several packets named by their latest date and followed by their inclusive dates. They are arranged by their most recent date, a bundle often encompass several days of news - often to track a particular story, politician, or issue. Several bundles begin with either an editorial cartoon or magazine article, and one (October 21) contains copies from the 2002 Pennsylvania Voters Guide.
    Subject focus is on the campaign issues prominent during the end of the gubernatorial 2002 campaign including schools/education underperformance, gambling, attack ads, endorsements, fund raising, taxes, abortion, and guns. Subjects vary by bundle and they may have served as daily media briefings for Mike Fisher.
    The Newslibrary Document Delivery materials are in regard to Ed Rendell's early political career, and despite originally being housed with the news clipping bundles their relation to the rest of this material is unknown.
    Duplicate bundles have been removed.
    - June 14th, 17th, and 26th packets, June 10-26, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - August 18th-23rd, 26th, and 28th packets, August 12-28, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - September 3rd-6th packets, August 21-September 6, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - September 9th-13th, 16th-17th, and 19th-20th packets, August 22-September, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - September 23rd-27th packets, September 8-27, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - September 30th packet, September 24-30, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - October 1st-4th packets, September 27-October 4, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - October 7th-11th packets, October 1-11, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - October 15th-18th packets, October 4-18, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - October 21st packet, October 13-21, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - October 23rd-25th packets, October 17-25, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - October 28th packet, October 23-28, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - October 29th packet, October 19-29, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - October 30th packet, October 23-30, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - October 31st packet, October 28-31, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - November 1st packet, October 27-November 1, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Newslibrary Document Delivery, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - News Clipping Subject Files, 2002; 10.
    All newsprint in this subseries are photocopied or printed, with the exception of folder 7: Loose newspapers and clippings.
    - Jane Earll, August 20 - September 25, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hershey Trust, August 7-30, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Daily News, May 13 - September 6, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Inquirer, May 11 - September 10, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Loose articles, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Many of these seem torn from or fallen out of the News Clipping Packets.
    - Various articles tagged by subject, May 28 - September 9, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Loose newspapers and clippings (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Personal Information, 1997-2002; 11.
    The Personal Information sub-series consists of tax and medical information about Mike Fisher and Jane Earll.
    - Income tax return - Jane M. Earll and John H. Daneri, 1998-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Income tax returns - D. Michael and Carol H. Fisher, 1997-2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - D. Michael Fisher medical records, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lt. Governor file - Jane Earll's bill of health, headshot, and various notes and clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Plans and Publications, 1996-2002; 12.
    The Plans and Publications sub-series is comprised of information on the Fisher/Earll gubernatorial agendas including plans for improving education, jobs, and senior citizen's services. This sub-series also includes information on reducing crime rate in Pennsylvania.
    - 1993-1998 Hate Crimes in Pennsylvania Report, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Attorney General Year in Review reports, 1997-2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Family Violence Task Force reports, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Fisher/Earll coalition, education and jobs plans (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - School safety, 2000-2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Seniors, 1996-2002 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Ed Rendell Files, 1995-2002; 13.
    The Ed Rendell Files sub-series is comprised of research conducted by the Fisher campaign into Ed Rendell's background and politics. It also includes detailed information on Rendell's campaign finance status.
    - Rendell financial information, 1995-2002 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Includes small amount of information on Bob Casey Jr. and Barbara Hafer's finances as well.
    - Rendell career and legislation research, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Tom Ridge and Mark Schweiker Files, 1994-2002; 14.
    The Tom Ridge and Mark Schweiker Files sub-series consists of accomplishments, initiatives, and publications of outgoing governors Tom Ridge and Mark Schweiker. Schweiker, Ridge's lieutenant governor, became governor when Ridge resigned to become Homeland Security Adviser to George W. Bush in 2001.
    - Policy initiatives and accomplishments, 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Gov. Schweiker publications, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Subject Files, 1986-2002; 15.
    The Subject Files sub-series includes materials that did not fit into the other sub-series of the Mike Fisher for Governor series. These include a sampled selection of petitions, debate information, publications unrelated to the Fisher campaign, and a heavily marked directory for Seton-La Salle, Elizabeth Seton, South Hills Catholic High Schools.
    - Briefing regarding National Association of Attorneys General (NAAG) multi-state report, October 5, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Debate at Easton Express Times, October 2002 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - General Election Almanac, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1986-2002 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Primary election materials (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Sampled petitions for Mike Fisher and Jane Earll with related correspondence (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Seton-La Salle High School, Elizabeth Seton High School, and South Hills Catholic High School Alumni Directory, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      Heavily bookmarked.
  - Tarrance Group Reports, 2000-2002; 16.
    The Tarrance Group Reports sub-series is comprised primarily of voter attitude surveys conducted by the Republican strategic research and polling consulting firm, The Tarrance Group. In addition to the voter surveys, there is a report with presentation slides analyzing the various gubernatorial candidates, but primarily focused on Mike Fisher, his campaign, and voter/newspaper perceptions of him and his political agenda.
    - A Survey of Voter Attitudes in Pennsylvania, February 2-3, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - A Survey of Voter Attitudes in Pennsylvania, December 2-3, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Tarrance Group report and presentation, February 8, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - A Survey of Voter Attitudes in Pennsylvania, September 3-4, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Schedules of Events, 2001-2003; 17.
    The Schedules of Events series comprises information on events that Fisher attended or was invited to. These files document when and where Fisher was during his gubernatorial campaign as well as the reasons he was there. Events include fundraisers, meet-and-greets, inaugurations, and other gatherings.
    - Schedule of Events 2002, December 31, 2001 - May 31, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Schedule of Events 2002, June 1 - October 2, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Schedule of Events 2002, October 3 - December 31, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Schedule of Events 2003, January 3 - June 2, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Schedule of Events 2003, June 3 - September 12, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Schedule of Events 2003, September 13 - December 11, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Post-2002 File, 2003-2004; VI.
  The Post-2002 File series contains the only two items in the D. Michael Fisher papers sub-group that date after 2002. Items are comprised of a calendar and Fisher's judicial installation ceremony pamphlet.
  - 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Attorney General Mike Fisher's 2004 Drug-Free Calendar, 1.
    - U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit installation ceremony pamphlet for Mike Fisher, December 15, 2003; 2.
- Memorabilia, 1969-1988; VII.
  The Memorobilia series is comprised of various objects commemorating different events in Fisher's life. They include objects relating to Fisher's professional life, such as certificates of election to the House of Representatives, as well as items like commemorative pens from legislation he worked to pass. Also included in this subseries is the certificate confirming Fisher as a certified attorney, and awards from local groups for him personally. Includes various certificates of election or achievement, community acknowledgements, membership notices, and awards.
  - Fisher certificates, 1969-1988 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Fisher awards, 1972-1998 (Box 16-17)
- Photographs, VIII.
  The Photographs series is comprised of slides and photographic prints of Mike Fisher's career, Kent Gates, and a variety of politicians posing alone or with Fisher/Gates.
  - Attorney General, 1996; 1.
    The Attorney General photos sub-series are comprised of images of Fisher on the campaing trail.
    - Attorney General Fisher photographs (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Aerial photographs of a mansion (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Gubernatorial Campaign, circa 2002; 2.
    The Gubernatorial Campaign photos are comprised of images of Fisher on the campaing trail. Subjects include posing with his family, Jane Earll, and President Bush.
    - Mike Fisher and family posing, 36 slides (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Mike Fisher posing with Jane Earll, 20 slides (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mike Fisher with President George W. Bush, 3 photographs (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Subject Photos, 291 photographs (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
      The topical photos include images of Mike Fisher with various individuals and groups. The photos include both posed and candid shots of Fisher. Subjects include Fisher with family, students, the elderly, farmers, Jane Earll, industry workers, and Fisher speaking at a town hall style meeting.
  - Mike Fisher Personal Photos, 3.
    The Undated Mike Fisher Photos sub-series includes photos of Fisher, Fisher golfing, Fisher's family, and Fisher with others (including politicians and other influential people) from various periods throughout Fisher's career.
    - Mike Fisher golfing, 10 photographs (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Mike Fisher with politicians, comstituents, and others, 25 photographs (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Mike Fisher and his family, 11 photographs (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Kent Gates, 4.
    - Kent Gates with politicians and a Regan headshot, 9 photographs (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania Politicians, 5.
    - Specter, Ridge, Schweiker, and Rendell photos, 8 photographs (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 6. (Box 15)
    The Miscellaneous subseries consists of a variety of Fisher photographs. Included are pictures with important political figures, as well as headshots of the politicians. There are personal photographs as well.
- Audio-Visual Material, IX.
  The Audio-Visual Material series is comprised of VHS and betacam cassette tapes of commercials, debates, interviews, and other materials created during the Fisher for Governor campaign. The vast majority of the commercials were created by the advertising firm, BrabenderCox. Three VHS cassettes fall outside the scope of the Fisher gubernatorial campaign, these are: a Joseph Kohn/Preate debate from October 1992 (2 tapes) and an October 1996 tape from the Black Attorneys Association candidates forum. The CDs were created by Fisher for Governor campaign staff and includes a BrabenderCox commercial, a database, press documents, local elected officials. Staff files are comprised of files created by Deputy Finance Directors Kristen Clark and Sarah Rajca; Policy Director David Sumner; and Research Director Ray Zaborney. The staff files contain emails, event information, form letters, fundraising information, information on opponents, issue research and talking points, memoranda, photographs, speeches, strategy and planning information.
  - Videos, 1992, 1999, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Video 1-33)
  - Videos, 1992, 1999, 2001-2002 (Box 14, Video 1-33)
  - CDs (Box 14, Disk 1-8)